ABBEY HUDSON

809 N. Spurgeon St., Apt. 11 Santa Ana, CA 92701 (949) 202-9622 A Hudson2@yahoo.com

Sales and marketing professional with a Bachelor of Arts in Communications Studies and more than eight years experience successfully establishing client relationships, developing and writing marketing materials, utilizing creative problem solving and improving processes. Demonstrated ability to effectively manage projects, resolve conflicts and work with internal teams and external clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Book Hill Partners/NSSTA, Washington D.C. (Telecommute)

Director of Communications and Marketing (August 2016 – Present)

- Develop and implement communications and marketing initiatives for the National Structured Settlements Trade Association (NSSTA).
- Manage NSSTA social media accounts, including YouTube, LinkedIn, Facebook and Twitter. Create content, curate items of interest for members and post to appropriate platform. Conduct a monthly YouTube search to ensure copyright compliance.
- Managed the NSSTA website redesign, including vendor selection, design guidance and approval, content updates and usability testing. Received training on making web updates in Drupal 8.
- Approve and manage the maintenance contract with the website vendor, continue to update the website and complete all improvements and changes outside of the maintenance contract. Create and promote content, including brochures, videos, monthly newsletters and weekly blogs.
- Cross promote NSSTA with member companies and related trade organizations. Collaborate to share content among partners. Build relationships with marketing professionals across the industry.
- Write and submit articles for publication in news outlets, trade industry magazines and online publications to educate the public and raise awareness about structured settlements.
- Monitor mentions of structured settlements and legislation in the media to ensure accurate information is being presented. Request corrections from authors and publications as necessary.
- Develop campaigns for marketing events. Schedule speakers and vendors, create marketing materials and act as on-site contact for members and guests in attendance.
- Develop targeted marketing campaigns for judges, attorneys, claims professionals and claimants.
- Run analytic reports on social media engagement. Blog posts are typically viewed by at least 50% of all association members. Have increased Facebook engagement by 25% over the last six months and web traffic has increased 34% since the relaunch of the site.

Pacific Life, Newport Beach, CA

Senior Internal Sales Associate (January 2014 – August 2016) Internal Sales Associate (January 2011 – January 2014)

• Provided excellent customer service to clients by maintaining high service levels and a professional demeanor through written and verbal communication. Handled escalated calls and resolve issues.

- Coordinated national seminars to provide training for clients and promote the company brand. Created and gave presentations. Solicited feedback on industry concerns and areas of opportunity.
- Used market analysis to create printed and online materials to successfully further the Pacific Life Structured Settlement product line.
- Attended conferences throughout the U.S. to establish relationships with sales representatives and promote the company brand.
- Wrote online content used to educate clients. Worked with teams across the company to make updates on a quarterly basis.
- Acted as the subject matter expert for department technical systems. Developed procedures, write job aides and conduct training to ensure consistent, effective and efficient use of systems.

Pacific Life, Newport Beach, CA

Business Development Analyst (December 2009 – January 2011) Business Development Support Specialist (September 2008 – December 2009)

- Reviewed and analyzed legal documents to ensure compliance with company standards and tax laws, utilizing attention to detail and critical thinking skills.
- Served as project lead to implement a new financial reporting system. Coordinated testing, data validation and implementation. Acted as the subject matter expert for the department.
- Implemented a case management system to ensure faster review of high priority documents.
- Identified and effectively communicated the consequences of non-compliant documents to clients and worked to create a mutually agreeable solution.

University of California, Irvine, CA

Office Manager (October 2007 – September 2008)

- Acted as manager for an office of 13 staff members and the Associate Dean of Computer Science, with an emphasis on special projects, budgeting and administrative tasks.
- Wrote marketing materials used for recruiting and student appreciation events.
- Successfully coordinated and marketed a conference for Computer Science teachers in California.
- Created annual budgets for student activities and operational costs; audited department accounts to ensure effective use of funds. Processed reimbursements and paid outstanding invoices.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Arts, Communication Studies, University of Nevada, Las Vegas
- Currently completing UCI Coding Bootcamp On track to complete the program 12/2017. Curriculum includes full-stack web development technologies/languages.

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Completed formal training classes in critical problem analysis/resolution, project management, meeting facilitation, effective interpersonal and written communication, proofreading and time management.